# Aquib Javed Khan

#### MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER - NI P

(+91) 95-8316-0009 |ajkhan357@gmail.com |aquibjk.wordpress.com/ |aquibjaved |aquib-javed-khan-795a7286/

## **Summary**

Currently, working as a Machine learning engineer in Tokopedia with more than two years of experience in the development and implementation of machine-learning models mainly focused on Natural Language Processing and Computer vision. Actively seeking a data scientist position to apply my experience and knowledge of machine learning in creating a valuable data implementation for Business.

## **Work Experience**

**TOKOPEDIA** 

Noida, India & Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb. 2018 - PRESENT

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

- IMAGE SEARCH: Custom Object detection using Yolo, Elastic search, TensorFlow, AutoEncoders
  Developed Image Search Engine, Users can directly search with images, currently working for fashion category
- FALLBACK RATES: K-NN, KDTree, Sci-kit learn, Flask for Rest API
  - Develop a model for orders which were lost during the rush hour of sale & high traffic API calls from logistics companies
  - $\circ\,$  Increased the number of orders placed by the end user and total profit by 4%
- OPERATIONAL CUSTOMER SUPPORT CHAT-BOT: Ngrams, Nearest Neighbor, Word Embeddings using FastText
  - o Built a model to predict the "type of questions" user is asking and respond back with respective solutions
  - o Designed a operational customer support team with minimal human resources increasing efficiency by 20%
- SMART REPLY: N-grams based model, CNN LSTM classifier, Keras, Flask
  - Implemented a model which understands the questions of end user and provides relevant solutions in the response box.
  - Reduced the response time between buyers and sellers by 16%

#### **TATA Consultancy Services**

Chennai, India

ASSISTANT SYSTEM ENGINEER & NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING ENGINEER

Feb. 2017 - Feb. 201

- NATURAL LANGUAGE SEARCH: Sci-kit learn, Spacy , Stanford NLP, CCG Parsing, Scala, Deep Learning Models
   Constructed a Natural language search pipeline which provides an unified access to applications in
- the platform
- Built a language model for Named Entity Recognition & Intent Classification which understands various types of query

#### **ETRIX Technologies**

Bhubaneswar, India

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER (INTERN)

May. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- Automated clothing classification system using transfer learning to classify the query image into its respective category
- · Applied Naive Bayes classifier with sci-kit learn library to design Intent classification in chatbot

### Skills

**Data Science :** Machine Learning, Deep learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing **Frameworks :** TensorFlow, Sci-kit Learn, OpenCV, Flask, Keras, Pandas, NumPy, FastText, Gensim

Languages: Python, Scala, MATLAB

## **Education**

Orissa Engineering College (Biju Patnaik University of Technology)

Bhubaneswar, India

B.TECH. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Aug. 2012 - May. 2016

## Extracurricular Activity

DISQOVERY 2016 (A competitive event to discover potential for solving societal challenges)

TCS Thane, India

Nov. 3- Nov. 7 2016

## **PARTICIPANT & WINNER**

- Worked on real time water quality monitoring system using IoT and Machine Learning
- Winner at Digital Impact Square 2016

JANUARY 17, 2019 ~~\*~~ AQUIB J.KHAN · RÉSUMÉ